<Document>
# Caesar's Legion

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://wiki.misfitsystems.net/index.php/Caesar's%20Legion"/]

<p>◈ Caesar's Legion ◈ Pactum Ferri - Legio Vera ◈ Salt Column ◈</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Caesar's Legion[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>◈ FACTION DOSSIER ◈</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active - Legio Vera / Pactum Ferri</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Bonneville Salt Flats, Utah
I-80 Corridor</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Commander[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Legate Ferro Maro (Salt Column)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Neo-Roman Tribalism
Order Through Absolute Discipline</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]Ave, true to Caesar[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Affiliation[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Pactum Ferri (Legio Vera)</Box>
  <Box>⬜ RESTRICTED ACCESS ⬜</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<p>[bold]Caesar's Legion[/bold] stands as a force of absolute order, forged from the conquest and assimilation of over eighty-six tribes across the former American Southwest. Built on the doctrines of Caesar himself, the Legion rejects the degeneracy of the Old World and the weakness of those who cling to its remnants.</p>
<p>[italic]Caesar is dead. The fire that forged the Legion has gone out. What survives the cooling will prove whether the work was real.[/italic]</p>
<p>The Legion's presence in this region belongs to the [bold]Salt Column[/bold], commanded by [bold]Legate Ferro Maro[/bold]. They have held the Bonneville Salt Flats for three years. They will continue to hold it.</p>

## History and Current Affairs

<h3 Text="The Death of Caesar"/>

<p>Caesar is gone. What he left behind is not grief - it is a question: what was built here, and does it stand without him? The Legion was designed to outlast its founder. Whether it does so depends entirely on the character of those who remain.</p>

<h3 Text="The Claim of Lacerta"/>

<p>Before his death, Caesar named no successor publicly. A man named Lacerta moved the moment Caesar fell. He destroyed the record of succession. He killed the witness. He put on the Laurels. These are not the actions of a man who was named. A man who was named has no reason to do any of that. [bold]Lacerta is a pretender.[/bold]</p>

<h3 Text="The Pactum Ferri"/>

<p>Two columns have aligned against Lacerta's advance.</p>
<ul>
<li>The [bold]Salt Column[/bold] under Legate Ferro Maro has held the Bonneville Salt Flats for three years. Ferro Maro is a man of arithmetic - Lacerta's character is settled, his trajectory is known, and Ferro Maro intends to stop him.</li>
<li>The [bold]Cinder Cohort[/bold] marches under Legate Verus Caldius. Where Ferro Maro is measured, Caldius is deliberate in a different way - he intends to make the cost of every mile felt, bleeding the pretender's column pass by pass until doubt spreads like rot through timber.</li>
</ul>
<p>Together these two columns form the [bold]Pactum Ferri[/bold], sometimes called [italic]Legio Vera[/italic]. They are not rebels. They are the Legion.</p>

<h3 Text="The Salt Column's Position"/>

<p>The Salt Column holds Wendover and the Bonneville Salt Flats, anchored along the I-80 corridor at the Utah-Nevada line. The flats offer no cover, no comfort, and no room for self-deception. This position commands the approach from the west. Lacerta's eventual advance from New Vegas runs through this ground.</p>
<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"The Salt Column has held this ground in conditions that would have broken a lesser force. We will continue to hold it. Ave. - Legate Ferro Maro, Salt Column, Caesar's Legion"[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

## The Code of the Legion

<p>Every Legionary, from the freshest Recruit to the Centurion himself, is bound by the will of Caesar. These are not suggestions - they are the sinew that holds the Legion together.</p>

<div>
<ul>
<li>Obey the orders of your superiors without question or delay</li>
<li>Wear your uniform and bear your arms as a servant of Caesar. You are his face in the wastes</li>
<li>Never kill a fellow servant of Caesar without just cause. Disputes of honor are settled through the duel</li>
<li>Do not rely on the crutches of the Old World. Stimpaks, advanced chems, and the armor of tyrants weaken the body and corrupt the spirit</li>
<li>Take no chems, alcohol, or narcotics. Acceptable remedies are those derived from the land</li>
<li>Prisoners taken in the field are a resource. Deal with them with creativity and purpose. Lethal force is permitted if they resist</li>
<li>Cannibalism is a taboo and is not to be discussed openly</li>
<li>The Legion does not attack those without cause</li>
<li>Technology captured in the field may be used at the Centurion's discretion. Radios, night-vision, and illumination tools are acceptable. Power armor, cyborg units, and medical beam weapons are not</li>
</ul>
</div>

## Command Structure

<p>The Legion operates through an unbroken chain of command. Authority flows downward. Obedience flows upward. There is no middle ground.</p>

<h3 Text="Command"/>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Rank[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Legate</Box>
  <Box>Command all Legion military operations in the region. Strategic decisions - troop movements, alliances, subjugation of factions - are yours. Caesar's will is expressed through you.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Centurion[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Lead combat operations. Execute the Legate's strategy in the field; commands the camp in full. His word is law within it, superseded only by the Legate.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Veteran Decanus[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Senior officer. Commands Veterans, Primes, and Legionaries in the field; answers directly to the Centurion.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Prime Decanus[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Commands Prime Legionaries and below. Carry out orders from above without question.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Recruit Decanus[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Junior officer responsible for managing and shaping newly inducted Legionaries. Lead a contubernium; follow orders without hesitation.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Line Ranks"/>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Rank[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Veteran Legionnaire[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>A hardened, proven Legionary. Fight, survive, and serve as the example your younger brothers are measured against.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Prime Legionnaire[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>A capable, seasoned Legionary who has demonstrated their worth. Execute orders. Fight as directed. Protect your brothers.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Legionnaire[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>A Legionary of the rank and file. Follows the orders of all Decani, the Centurion, and those above. Discipline at all times.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Special Roles"/>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Explorer (Venator)[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Scout the region. Gather intelligence. Track persons of interest. Operates with more autonomy than line Legionaries - ranging ahead to assess threats, working alone or in pairs.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Frumentarii[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Agents of intelligence and infiltration. Infiltrate, observe, and report. Sow discord among the Legion's enemies. Eliminate high-value targets when ordered. [italic]The Frumentarii do not exist - and that is the point.[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Houndmaster[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Responsible for the Legion's war dogs and their deployment in battle and scouting. Animals are Legion assets; care for them accordingly.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Vexillarius[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Carry the Legion's standard. Rally brothers, maintain cohesion under fire, and protect the standard at all costs. Where you stand, the Legion stands.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Optio[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Speak for the Legion. Deal with non-Legion parties, broadcast Caesar's ideology, and manage faction reputation with communities that can be brought into compliance without force.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Camp Roles"/>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Auxilia[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Women who provide essential functions within the camp. Respected members of the Legion's support structure. Non-combative.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Recruit[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>You are at the bottom. Follow every order. Do not question above your station. Every great Centurion started where you are standing.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Slave[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>The lowest station. Slaves serve all above them and are marked by collar and tattoo. Put to work farming, cooking, mining, crafting, and healing. Faithful labor is protected; insubordination is punished up to crucifixion. Loyal slaves may in time be elevated.</Box>
</Table>

## Medical Provisions

<p>The Legion rejects the chemical degeneracy of the Old World. The body is a weapon; to poison it with manufactured substances is to dishonor Caesar.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Substance[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Permitted[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Healing Powder / Poultice, Regenerative Mesh, Mourning Poultice, Ephedra (Ephi), Charcoal, Saline Glucose, Mannitol / Neurine, RadAway (extreme radiation exposure only)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Forbidden[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Morphine, Rad-X, Stimpaks, Brute/Burn Patches, Med-X, Jet, Buffout, Psycho, Alcohol</Box>
</Table>

<p>[italic]Note: RadAway is found naturally in Punga. Use only when a Legionary faces severe radiation exposure. Bagged sources found in the field are acceptable.[/italic]</p>

## Prisoners and Slaves

<p>[bold]Prisoners[/bold] taken in the field are a resource to be managed with intelligence and purpose, not simply disposed of. A prisoner may serve as leverage, a labor source, an intelligence asset, or a candidate for eventual service. Officers are expected to exercise judgment. Crucifixion is available as a sentence - but it is not the default answer to every capture.</p>
<p>[bold]Slaves[/bold] within the camp serve at the pleasure of Caesar's Legion and are under the protection of its members, provided they conduct themselves with obedience and humility. They are not to be abused arbitrarily - the Legion requires their labor and cooperation. Insubordination, refusal to work, or disrespect toward Legionaries will be met with appropriate consequences.</p>

</Document>
